[Music]
[音乐]
okay I think it's time to start I know
好吧，我想是时候开始了，我知道
it's the last session so thank you for
这是最后一次会议，谢谢你
coming for this talk and I'm happy that
来参加这个演讲，我很高兴
so many people to listen to my talk and
这么多人听我的演讲，
as you can see I will talk today about
如您所见，我今天将谈论
how to do scheduling in a distributed
如何在分布式中进行调度
systems and especially of the
系统，尤其是
applications that are written using
使用编写的应用程序
spring
弹簧
my name is Marrakech crime coming from
我的名字叫马拉喀什犯罪，来自
Poland but currently I'm working for and
波兰，但目前我在为
26 in Berlin we have also office closeby
26在柏林，我们附近还有办公室
in Barcelona and pretty fresh office in
在巴塞罗那，在
Vienna so the company is growing a lot
维也纳，因此公司发展迅速
but also we do of course some
但我们当然也做一些
interesting technical things and this is
有趣的技术问题，这是
one of the topics that I want to cover
我要介绍的主题之一
so let's start and look what's the
所以让我们开始看看是什么
agenda for today so at the beginning I
今天的议程，所以一开始我
will talk about the background about
将谈论有关的背景
what the what kind of process we wanted
我们想要什么样的过程
to solve and why we introduced this one
解决以及为什么我们引入这一
what you will see soon then I will show
你很快会看到什么然后我会显示
two different approaches because we
两种不同的方法，因为我们
believe that usually the problem should
认为通常问题应该
be solved in an evolutionary way so we
以进化的方式解决，所以我们
usually try something simple we check if
通常尝试一些简单的事情，我们检查是否
does it work or not and then we move on
它是否有效，然后我们继续
if there is a requirement to improve
如果需要改进
that in the meantime and also at the end
在此期间以及最后
I will show a few results what what did
我将显示一些结果
work what didn't and what are the
工作什么没有，什么是
conclusions and what are potential ways
结论和潜在的方法是什么
to improve things so let's jump into the
改善事情，让我们跳进
problem that we tried to solve before
我们之前试图解决的问题
actually going into the the whole
实际上进入整体
problem that I wanted to show you let me
我想告诉你的问题让我
do a short introduction of how the
简要介绍如何
systems in our company are basically
我们公司的系统基本上是
developed and how we try to do things so
发达，以及我们如何尝试这样做
in the past at the beginning of of the
在过去的开始
lifetime of the company we've been doing
我们一直在做的公司的一生
most most of the things with synchronous
大多数事情与同步
communications so traditional HTTP
通讯如此传统的HTTP
communication but we know that this is
沟通，但我们知道这是
not the best way we we also try to do to
不是我们也尝试做的最好方法
hand a lot of traffic so we do the
交了很多流量，所以我们做到了
things with the events so this is why we
与事件有关的事情，这就是为什么我们
have interns across
有实习生
education in our company and in this
我们公司的教育
sense I mean that we send events between
我是说我们之间发送事件
the between the services and it's not of
服务之间的关系不是
course always possible so we have still
当然总是可能的，所以我们仍然
some synchronized way to handle
一些同步的方式来处理
especially if the process like business
特别是如果流程像业务
case requires that there is the need to
案例要求有必要
receive a response immediately but if
立即收到回应，但如果
you can do some things in a dealer with
你可以在经销商那里做一些事情
a dealer then this but that's basically
经销商然后这个，但这基本上是
using events is the best way to go
使用事件是最好的方式
also the an additional benefit of of a
还有一个额外的好处
synchronous communications is processing
同步通讯正在处理中
that is now more reliable so because we
现在更可靠了，因为我们
use AWS and their solution for four
使用AWS及其解决方案有四个
streams is called Canaries they have
溪流被称为金丝雀
this guarantee that each event will be
这保证了每个事件都会
delivered at least once to the service
至少一次交付给服务
so then it means that you kind of push
所以这意味着你有点推
the responsibility to the different
对不同的责任
service that a different solution and
服务于另一种解决方案，
they guarantee you that you will not
他们保证您不会
lose anything which is not always the
失去的东西并不总是
case in a synchronous communication and
在同步通信中
also I like the visibility that in
我也喜欢
events communication provides because
事件交流之所以提供，是因为
now we can have some some screen on
现在我们可以在一些屏幕上
which we can display how many events are
我们可以显示多少个事件
gonna be processed by a bio service and
将由生物服务处理，
how for example how is the service how
例如如何服务
fast he is handling the communication so
他正在快速处理通讯，所以
if it's falling behind in the
如果它落后于
communication in falling behind in the
沟通落后于
processing of the events so having that
处理事件，因此
in mind that this is how how we try to
请记住，这就是我们如何尝试
solve things in our company let's look
解决我们公司里的事情
at the problem that we've been having so
在我们一直遇到的问题上
here you can see the simplified view of
在这里您可以看到的简化视图
the problem that we were trying to solve
我们试图解决的问题
so from the left side we have this event
所以从左侧开始
stream so in our case it's a canal
流，所以在我们的情况下，这是一条运河
stream and we we have we have some
流，我们有我们有一些
events coming from from the stream some
来自流的事件
now let's let's think about something
现在让我们考虑一下
abstract an event is received by an
摘要事件被接收
application and we have a component in
应用程序，我们有一个组件
our application which we call stream
我们称为流的应用程序
consumer it basically reads the item
消费者，它基本上是阅读商品
from the stream and filters out the
从信息流中过滤出
events that are
发生的事件
important father for the service because
服务的重要父亲，因为
they can be of course different events
他们当然可以是不同的事件
that are not important in for our
对我们来说不重要
application and we what we do is we
应用程序，我们所做的就是我们
store each event into the database
将每个事件存储到数据库中
each important event for the service we
服务的每个重要事件
store into database you can ask why we
存储到数据库中，您可以问为什么
are doing this actually why the database
在这样做实际上是为什么数据库
is needed we believe that reading the
需要，我们认为阅读
stream should be as fast as possible so
流应该尽可能快
storing all the events that we want to
存储我们想要的所有事件
process into the database make the
进入数据库的过程
process that the consumer that reads
阅读的消费者的过程
that the event from the stream kind of
流中的事件
fast and if there would be some logic
快速，如果有逻辑的话
needed to process the event it would
需要处理事件
take down and in this case if we store
取下来，在这种情况下，如果我们存储
it into database which is usually super
它进入数据库通常是超级
fast then the stream consumer can move
很快，流消费者就可以移动
forward and can process the each events
转发并可以处理每个事件
so this is how we improved improved the
所以这就是我们改进改进的方式
way how we process the stream but also
我们如何处理流的方式
now we can store the the data into the
现在我们可以将数据存储到
database and if the same event will be
数据库，如果相同的事件将
received for the second time that can
第二次收到可以
happen then now we have a source of true
发生了，那么现在我们有一个真实的来源
ok we store this event we don't need to
好的，我们不需要存储此事件
handle it again and we can move on with
再次处理它，我们可以继续
the meaning of the streams and the
流的含义和
second part on the right side there is a
右侧的第二部分有一个
scheduler so the there is this job that
调度程序，所以有这项工作
I will be talking mostly during this
在此期间，我将主要谈论
talk that we read something from the
谈论我们从
database the events that are stored
数据库存储的事件
there and we process them maybe perform
在那里，我们处理它们也许执行
perform some logic now is the time for
现在执行一些逻辑
performing the logic because we didn't
执行逻辑，因为我们没有
do this on the streaming consumer
在流媒体消费者上执行此操作
because thought was just fast and when
因为思想很快，什么时候
we process this we need to store this
我们处理这个，我们需要存储这个
into the external service so basically
基本上就是进入外部服务
this is the use case event is received
这是用例事件
and we stored this into an external
并将其存储到外部
service
服务
so let's look how how how this can be
让我们来看看如何
done in a spring application so probably
在春季应用中完成，所以大概
this is a part of code that most of you
这是你们大多数人的代码的一部分
already written or at least seen it so
已经写过或者至少看过了
we have a simple service we mark it with
我们有一个简单的服务，我们用
a notation components on our spring can
我们弹簧上的符号组件可以
find it in it the service can be
可以在其中找到服务
injected into the different components
注入不同的组件
and we have a method that runs quite
而且我们有一种方法可以很好地运行
often and processes the events what we
经常处理事件
have in the database and we can mark it
在数据库中，我们可以对其进行标记
ok it's not it's now we want to have it
好吧不是现在我们想要它
quite often so we mark it with another
很多时候，所以我们用另一个标记
rotation available from the spring and
从弹簧和
we say okay let's run it that often as
我们说好吧，让我们经常运行
the cron expression set so cron
cron表达式设置为cron
expression is probably also pretty known
表达可能也很出名
for before for all of you but it's just
对于你们所有人之前的事情，但这只是
an expression coming from the UNIX
来自UNIX的表达式
environment and you can basically define
环境，您基本上可以定义
how often something should happen and in
应该多久发生一次
this case the first digit the first
这种情况下第一个数字第一个
position zero that just says that when
零位只是说什么时候
the clock arrives to time that has zero
时钟到达零的时间
seconds and any other number is just
秒和任何其他数字仅仅是
different than just any you it should
与您应该有的不同
trigger so basically it will trigger
触发，所以基本上它将触发
every minute at the zero seconds of
在零秒的每一分钟
clock but as you can imagine this simple
时钟，但您可以想象这很简单
solution works only when you have one
解决方案仅在您拥有一个时才有效
single machine and in our company amount
单机和我们公司的数量
of customers and amount of traffic in
的客户数量和流量
the system is really high so we need to
系统真的很高，所以我们需要
we need to scale we need to make the
我们需要扩展规模，我们需要
application grow so this is why we have
应用程序增长，所以这就是为什么
to talk about distributed systems and in
谈论分布式系统以及
distributed systems there are two ways
分布式系统有两种方式
to scale the old one called horizontal
缩放旧的称为水平的
or vertical scaling so going up it means
或垂直缩放，因此上升意味着
that you basically make the service that
您基本上是在提供服务
is handing the traffic much stronger at
正在使流量更强大
CPU you add memory and makes it much
CPU，您增加了内存并增加了内存
stronger and now it can handle more
更强大，现在可以处理更多
traffic but actually when you go with
交通，但实际上当您与
this solution everyone probably under
这个解决方案大家可能都在
understands that this doesn't work
知道这行不通
especially in the cloud where you have a
特别是在云中
limited amount of servers that you can
您可以限制的服务器数量
buy and there is always a highest the
购买，总是有最高的
best server you can buy and it cost a
您可以购买的最好的服务器，它的成本是
lot of money but this still may be at
很多钱，但这仍然可能
some moment not efficient enough so we
有一段时间效率不高，所以我们
can say okay vertical scanning actually
可以说垂直扫描还可以
doesn't scale so the other way to go of
不能缩放，所以另一种方法
course is the horizontal scaling so
当然是水平缩放
moving left and right and adding more
左右移动并添加更多
nodes of the same machine and probably
同一台机器的节点，可能
it's pretty known in the in the solution
在解决方案中这是众所周知的
in the community why we do this but
在社区中为什么我们这样做，但是
let's name few few benefits first cost
让我们先列举几个好处
efficiency usually few nodes much
效率通常很少几个节点
smaller ones much cheaper ones perform
较小的便宜得多的表演
or perform better at or at least the
或至少在以下方面表现更好
same as one big machine so this is the
和一台大机器一样，所以这是
first benefit another one high
先受益再高
reliability we have multiple nodes one
可靠性，我们有多个节点
goes down the other can handle the
掉下来其他可以处理
traffic
交通
also easier to expand of course we have
当然也更容易扩展
three notes why do not add three mores
三个笔记为什么不加三个
and just load bar until behind at the
然后加载酒吧直到后面的
traffic so having that in mind let's
交通，因此请记住
look at the other at our problem so our
看看对方在我们的问题上，所以我们
problem was that we had a scheduled job
问题是我们有预定的工作
and now we want to run it on multi now
现在我们要在多点运行它
it would run on multiple notes which is
它会在多个音符上运行
usually not what you want to achieve so
通常不是您想要达到的目标
this is why we had this problem how to
这就是为什么我们有这个问题的原因
run this scheduled logic on a single
一次运行此计划的逻辑
note and why because you don't want to
注意，为什么，因为你不想
repeat up also from the resource usage
从资源使用情况也重复
but also maybe the business case just
但也许只是商业案例
not doesn't allow you to repeat to solve
不允许您重复解决
this problem of running on a single note
单音符运行的问题
you need to have two information or like
您需要两个信息或类似信息
to two problems to solve because we have
要解决两个问题，因为我们有
now multiple notes you have to select
现在您必须选择多个音符
one that will solve that will run this
一个将解决的将运行此
scheduled job and you also need to have
预定的工作，你还需要
this information stored somewhere
这些信息存储在某个地方
because the other notes need to know
因为其他笔记需要知道
okay I'm not longer the note to run the
好的，我不再需要运行
scheduler so I will just go over and
调度程序，所以我将过去
sleep more so let's look at the other
多睡一会，让我们看看另一个
whole system how it could look like so
整个系统看起来像这样
we have three instances let's say for
我们有三个实例
just for the sake of example and the
仅出于示例和
instances actually could communicate
实例实际上可以交流
between each other and they could say
彼此之间，他们可以说
maybe we can agree on between us that
也许我们可以在我们之间达成共识
one of us should be a leader but the
我们中的一个应该成为领导者，但是
approach in spring and I suppose also in
春天来了，我想也是
other frameworks is that the the notes
其他框架是，注意事项
are pretty stateless so basically they
相当无状态，所以基本上
are alone kind of standing and they
独自站立，他们
don't even know that there are other
甚至不知道还有其他
instances handling the same and if you
实例处理相同，如果
would think that they should now then
会认为他们现在应该
comes to like network how they
变得像网络一样
communicate if you have different
交流，如果你有不同
virtual machines maybe you have
虚拟机也许你有
different docker containers so how they
不同的Docker容器，它们如何
can communicate is this the same machine
可以沟通是同一台机器
maybe it's a different network so to
也许是一个不同的网络，所以
simplify let's say the communication
简化说，沟通
between between this node was not a case
在这个节点之间不是一个案例
for us especially if we wanted to
对我们来说，特别是如果我们想
provide something fast and have a simple
快速提供东西，简单
solution that would work well it would
效果很好的解决方案
work so we didn't go this way this is
工作，所以我们没有这样走
why we try
为什么我们尝试
we introduce something somewhat some
我们介绍一些
else some on a solution that will
其他一些解决方案将
basically solve it for us as an
基本上为我们解决了
introduction of another component so
因此引入了另一个组件
this is why we thought okay now we need
这就是为什么我们认为现在需要
a place that will store this information
一个将存储此信息的地方
for us let's call it it could be a cache
对我们来说，它可能是缓存
it could be a database I've heard during
可能是我在听过的数据库
the conference that people were solving
人们正在解决的会议
this with Mongo it can be different
这与Mongo可能会有所不同
different different solutions but
不同的解决方案，但
basically this place has to be reliable
基本上这个地方必须可靠
of course because we don't want to
当然是因为我们不想
introduce more failing points and it
引入更多的失败点，它
will basically do two things first it
首先会做两件事
will store the information which no it
将存储没有的信息
should be a leader but also it will
应该是一个领导者，但也会
allow this communication between the
允许
instance and an Orchestrator as we can
一个实例和一个Orchestrator
call it differently and provided the
用不同的方式称呼它并提供
answer to a question am i a leader is
我是领导者的问题的答案是
the instance that has been just
只是一个实例
triggered by the chronic by the crown by
由王冠触发的慢性经
the scheduled to run the process the
预定运行过程
events am i a leader and only if this
活动是领导者，且仅当
this note will receive the answer only
这则笔记只会得到答案
then it will process process the events
然后它将处理事件
in the in the Lottery's so having that
在彩票中
in mind let's think how we could how we
让我们考虑一下如何才能
could solve that so coming back to the
可以解决这个问题，所以回到
original question because we are in a
最初的问题，因为我们在
spring spring based application so to
弹簧基于弹簧的应用程序所以
specify it even more we have multiple
指定更多，我们有多个
notes all the applications are spring
注意所有的应用都是春季
applications and we want to select one
应用程序，我们要选择一个
as the leader and let's let's look at
作为领导者，让我们来看看
the code again so we had this simple
再次编写代码，所以我们有了这个简单的方法
service already visible here and we have
服务已经在这里可见，我们有
it was working and now let's see how it
它正在工作，现在让我们看看它如何
can be done in a distributed world so
可以在分布式世界中完成
we've used already one annotation at
我们已经在使用了一个注释
scheduled so maybe we can use another
预定的，所以也许我们可以使用另一个
one this time our custom and let's name
这次我们的习俗之一，让我们命名
it run if leader so this this in this
它运行，如果领导者，这在这个
sense we have now a method that is
感觉我们现在有一种方法是
pretty please pretty clear right if you
如果可以，请清楚清楚
look at it okay it does some scheduled
看着好吧，它做了一些预定的
job but only if there if the note on
工作，但前提是有
which this not this code will run is a
这不是此代码将运行的是
leader so let's move into the into the
领导者，让我们进入
details how this can be implemented
详细说明如何实现
so writing your own annotation is pretty
所以写自己的注释很漂亮
simple it was visible on many talks to
很简单，在许多对话中都可以看到
today and yesterday but actually no one
今天和昨天，但实际上没有人
at least I didn't hear no one went into
至少我没有听说没有人参加
the details what's the what is this two
详细情况这是什么两个
properties that you need to add to that
您需要添加到的属性
interface so it's called interface but
接口，所以称为接口，但是
it's just a nomenclature on on the Java
这只是Java上的术语
that you need to create a class with
您需要创建一个类
this add interface and you basically
这个添加界面，你基本上
need to provide these two properties the
需要提供这两个属性
first property is a retention and
第一个属性是保留权，
basically tells to the Java JVM or
基本上告诉Java JVM或
compiler where this annotation should
注释应在哪里编译
stay so the retention that we used here
留下来，我们在这里使用的保留
is the runtime so basically it says that
是运行时，基本上它说
this retention should stay for the whole
这种保留应该保留整个
life cycle of the application till the
应用程序的生命周期，直到
runtime so let's say compiler could
运行时，所以说编译器可以
remove some annotations but this one no
删除一些注释，但是这个没有
it has to state a lifetime because in
它必须声明一生，因为
our case of course if it would be
我们的情况当然会
removed by the compiler how running code
由编译器删除如何运行代码
could check if the if the note on which
可以检查是否在
we are running something is a leader so
我们正在运行的东西是领导者，所以
having that in mind the retention is the
考虑到这一点，保留是
first target is the second one target is
第一个目标是第二个目标是
simple just Mark's work that says where
马克说的很简单
you can put this annotation and for us
您可以放置​​此注释，并为我们
it's a method so it could be a class but
这是一个方法，所以它可能是一个类，但是
of course this is what what we want to
当然这就是我们想要的
have okay
没事
let's let's go deeper because this is
让我们更深入，因为这是
just a annotation and now we need to
只是一个注释，现在我们需要
somehow understand how this annotation
以某种方式理解这个注释
can be understood by the spring so this
可以被春天理解
is why we need to introduce
这就是为什么我们需要介绍
aspect-oriented programming so
面向方面的程序设计
aspect-oriented programming is it's just
面向方面的编程仅仅是
a name but basically what it says is
一个名字，但基本上说的是
that an aspect is a concern that cuts
一个方面是削减的关注点
through the whole application so a
通过整个应用程序
concern that is attached to all the it
关注所有
could be attached to all the business
可以附属于所有业务
logic in the application next to the
应用程序旁边的逻辑
database next to the service next to the
服务旁边的数据库
controller so one example that is pretty
控制器，所以一个漂亮的例子
commonly said when someone explains AOP
通常在有人解释AOP时说
it's logging because logging is
它正在记录日志，因为日志记录是
something that we do every day and we
我们每天做的事情，我们
put it on every part of the application
放在应用程序的每个部分
so this is why is a cross-cutting
所以这就是为什么跨领域
concern also commonly named here is
关注这里也俗称
transaction management this is
交易管理这是
I think that we do in different business
我认为我们从事不同的业务
processes so it's not something that is
处理，所以这不是什么
attached to a specific problem also cuts
附加到特定问题上也可以减少
the whole application how how we can
整个应用程序如何
having that in mind hack how we can now
考虑到这一点，我们现在该如何
enable that in the public in the spring
春季在公众场合启用
no surprise here we just add new
毫不奇怪，我们只需添加新
dependency so spring would starter AOP
依赖，因此春季将启动AOP
and now spring can find our annotations
现在春天可以找到我们的注释
and can process them why it was done
并可以处理他们这样做的原因
like that
像那样
I suppose the outers of spring thought
我想春天的想法
okay maybe we can enable for people to
好吧，也许我们可以使人们
to introduce their annotations but it's
介绍他们的注释，但这是
not something that common so the core
不是那么常见的东西，所以核心
spring doesn't have this so you can use
春天没有这个，所以你可以使用
of course annotations but if you want to
当然是注解，但是如果您想
create your own you need this dependency
创建自己的需要这种依赖
okay that would that would work that
好吧，那会工作的
could enable the an application but how
可以启用该应用程序，但是如何
actually we can really teach spring that
其实我们真的可以教春天
there is an annotation and what it
有一个注释及其内容
should do to understand that we need to
应该了解我们需要
introduce the concept of advices so that
介绍建议的概念，以便
free advices they're actually more but
免费的建议，他们实际上更多，但
let's focus on the three the most simple
让我们专注于最简单的三个
ones so advice is a concept of saying
因此，建议是说
please on the runtime process this
请在运行时过程中
annotation at a specific moment in time
在特定时间的注释
and in our case is a method so we say
在我们的情况下是一种方法，所以我们说
maybe this advice that we will write
也许我们会写的这个建议
that will that will check for us if the
那将检查我们是否
note is the leader could run after so
请注意，领导者可以追赶
for us of course after is already too
对我们来说当然也已经
late because the job would perform so we
迟到了，因为工作会执行，所以我们
can cross it out so maybe before could
可以把它划掉，所以也许可以
be could be used for us but before it's
可以用于我们，但在此之前
an unconditional one so before advice
一个无条件的建议
says this code it will be gone will run
说这段代码将消失将运行
never know whatever happens this code
永远都不知道这段代码会发生什么
will run and we can add some logic be
将运行，我们可以添加一些逻辑是
some code before for example log so
一些代码，例如登录之前，所以
logging could be also handled by out by
日志记录也可以由
by aspects and you could say before this
按方面，你可以在此之前说
method always look but unfortunately is
方法总是看起来，但不幸的是
unconditional and in our case we need
无条件的，就我们而言，我们需要
use around which adds this possibility
使用周围增加了这种可能性
to proceed only when specific condition
仅在特定条件下进行
is met let's look at how finally we can
满足，让我们看看最终如何
implement this
实现这个
vice so - how we can use this advisor so
副主席-我们如何使用这个顾问
to have this we have to create our own
要拥有这个，我们必须创造我们自己的
aspect and originally in spring the
方面，最初是在春季
aspects were defined in XML and probably
方面是用XML定义的，可能
most of you don't use anymore that so we
你们大多数人不再使用了，所以我们
can use annotations annotations are
可以使用注释注释
coming from aspectj framework so this is
来自aspectj框架，所以这是
why you can see these two annotations
为什么您可以看到这两个注释
aspect and around these two are coming
方面和这两个即将到来
from this framework and basically when
从这个框架，基本上什么时候
you have this method this class here you
你在这个班上有这个方法
need to create one method and annotate
需要创建一种方法并注释
it with one of the advices that you've
它与您已经提出的建议之一
seen on the previous slide and inside
在上一张幻灯片和内部看到
this around you basically define how it
你周围的这个基本上定义了它如何
should match and first what you can see
应该匹配，首先您可以看到
on the slide is that it has to match the
在幻灯片上的是它必须匹配
annotation with the name that we defined
具有我们定义的名称的注释
few slides before and it also has to
几张幻灯片之前，它也必须
match an execution of a method that
匹配执行方法
returns nothing this is why void and it
什么也不返回，这就是为什么虚无的原因
has any name and any list of parameters
有任何名称和任何参数列表
okay so now this one will match the
好吧，现在这将匹配
annotation that we will put on a
我们将放置在
specific part of the code but the the
代码的特定部分，但
logic has to be inside this is why we
逻辑必须放在里面这就是为什么我们
need to introduce the last part of a op2
需要介绍op2的最后一部分
to close the whole topic of the
关闭整个主题
annotation we need to have the join
注释，我们需要加入
point and the join point is a point in
点和连接点是一个点
the code when the application rounds and
应用程序四舍五入时的代码和
when the application runs so they so the
当应用程序运行时，因此
application runs executes something then
应用程序运行然后执行一些操作
is the point and then a something next
是重点，然后是下一步
runs etc etc and before our code will
运行等等等，然后我们的代码将
run there will be a join point just a
运行会有一个连接点
moment in time before running it and
在运行它之前及时
this is when this annotation will kick
这是该注释将启动的时间
in and as you can see in the code that
在您所看到的代码中
we will basically check if this node is
我们将基本上检查该节点是否为
a leader we will only then proceed with
一个领导者，我们只会继续
the join point and in the other case if
连接点，在其他情况下
not then we will just pass just will
不那么我们只会通过
skip the execution and again here I will
跳过执行，然后再次在这里
not go too much into details regarding
不要过多地关注有关的细节
the leadership how it is selected how
领导如何选择
it's implemented because it depends on
之所以实现，是因为它取决于
the solution that you that you selected
您选择的解决方案
so in our case it was it was a note that
所以在我们的情况下，这是一个说明
we could basically use
我们基本上可以使用
HTTP call but it could be whatever else
HTTP调用，但也可以是其他任何一种
you decide to use there okay so having
您决定使用那里，所以
that in mind that that solved the
考虑到那解决了
problem it was working for us but we
问题是它为我们工作，但我们
found out that there were few things
发现几乎没有东西
that we didn't like it so let's talk
我们不喜欢它，所以让我们谈谈
about the disadvantages of this solution
关于此解决方案的缺点
first first thing that I want to mention
我想提的第一件事
is the separation of business logic and
是业务逻辑的分离和
the scheduling logic so as you can as
调度逻辑，以便您尽可能
you saw on the slide we have this ad
您在幻灯片上看到我们有这则广告
scheduled annotation just above the
排在上方的预定注释
method that does something so someone
做某人的方法
would say that in solid principles when
会说，以扎实的原则
you have a single single responsibility
你有一个单一的责任
principle
原理
you shouldn't shouldn't mix that we
你不应该不混合我们
agree on that and we thought that maybe
对此表示同意，我们认为也许
it could be solved better also we found
我们可以找到更好的解决方案
out that it was not that easy to test so
出来测试不是那么容易，所以
we have this annotation but writing a
我们有这个注释，但是写了一个
simple unit test verifying that this
简单的单元测试，以验证
part of code is scheduled and that this
代码的一部分已经安排好了
part of code will run that often as we
代码的一部分会像我们一样经常运行
want was not obvious and the last we we
想要并不明显，最后我们
found out that when the application
发现当申请
start to grow we had more and more jobs
开始增长，我们有越来越多的工作
scheduled and it became a little bit
预定，变得有点
much because the jobs were spread
很大程度上是因为工作分散了
through the application and if someone
通过应用程序，如果有人
would like to verify what are the tasks
想验证什么任务
happening in the background it's not
在后台发生的不是
that easy you would not you would need
如此简单，您将不需要
basically to search through the whole
基本上可以搜索整个
application I want to also talk before
我之前也想谈的应用程序
switching to the second approach I want
切换到我想要的第二种方法
to talk about one problem that one
谈论一个问题
specific problem that we had with this
我们遇到的具体问题
solution so we also use from the AWS
解决方案，因此我们也可以从AWS使用
cloud there is a queue solution called
云中有一个称为队列的解决方案
sqs and this queue can be used with
sqs，此队列可以与
client provided by AWS and the client
由AWS提供的客户端和客户端
insights there uses this as a sqs
那里的见解将其用作平方
listener another annotation
侦听器另一个注释
everythings annotation so having that
一切都是注释，因此
we could implement something like a
我们可以实现类似
non-event method that you have here and
您在此处使用的非事件方法
you can basically see that
你基本上可以看到
condition of that is pretty easy you
这样的条件很容易
just say okay this is the value value
只是说好，这就是价值
this case name of the queue that you
您的队列的这种情况名称
want to listen to and this is the
想听，这是
deletion policy when something should be
什么时候应该删除政策
removed from the queue this unsuccess
从队列中删除此不成功
means that if the method proceeded
表示如果该方法继续进行
without any exception it was all good so
毫无例外，一切都很好，所以
now the message can be removed and how
现在可以删除该消息以及如何
this is working is that the note that
这是有效的是，注意
runs this takes a message from from a
运行此命令会从
queue makes it invisible for other nodes
队列使其对其他节点不可见
and processes it but in this case the
并处理它，但在这种情况下
node would take it and make market
节点会抓住它并赢得市场
invisible and will check if it is a
看不见，会检查它是否是
leader mark making it impossible to read
前导标记，使其无法阅读
by the other nodes so that's pretty
由其他节点，这很漂亮
inefficient and at the beginning people
效率低下的人
were not that sure what's happening
不确定发生了什么
because what could be wrong using some
因为使用一些可能出了什么问题
annotations right but actually looks
注释正确，但实际上看起来
like the order of the annotations
像注解的顺序
probably should be different and you
可能应该与您不同
couldn't you should never read something
难道你不应该读任何东西
from SQL because because doesn't make
从SQL，因为因为没有
any sense to even try reading something
甚至尝试阅读任何东西
from the SQL if you are not a leader and
从SQL，如果您不是领导者，并且
if you just follow if you are new in a
如果您只是跟随，如果您是新手
team and you don't know what is
团队，你不知道是什么
happening and you are just following
发生，而你只是在跟随
other part of the codes and basically
代码的其他部分，基本上
copying pasting SQL listener you don't
复制您不粘贴的SQL侦听器
go into details maybe you don't
进入细节也许你不
understand that actually then the
知道实际上
message will be not visible for some
某些消息将不可见
time if if the the check on the leader
时间是否如果检查领导
is is taking some time okay this is why
需要一些时间，这就是为什么
we tried something else we decided that
我们尝试了其他事情，我们决定
maybe we should switch to another
也许我们应该切换到另一个
approach which is called programmatic
称为程序化的方法
approach programmatic it means that you
以程序方式进行处理意味着您
need to write a little bit more code but
需要多写一些代码，但是
you have a much better control of the of
您可以更好地控制
the way how we want to schedule so like
我们想要如何安排的方式
let's look how how this can be done to
让我们看看如何做到这一点
have this we don't know we all switch
有这个，我们不知道我们都切换了
out of the annotations so maybe that's
在注释之外，所以也许是
already benefit for some of us and we
已经为我们中的一些人受益，我们
now need to implement interface with the
现在需要实现与
name scheduling configure that is
名称调度配置即
available from this package and this is
可从此包装中获得，这是
something a standard code of spring
弹簧的标准代码
and having that in mind writing that is
并记住这是
it's pretty simple because the interface
这很简单，因为界面
just has one method the method says it
方法只有一种
will configure the task and it provide
将配置任务，并提供
you a registrar and on this registrar
您是注册商，并且在此注册商
you will basically call all the things
你基本上会把所有的东西
that you want to scale and one
您想要缩放的一个
additional benefit that I will show in
我将展示的其他好处
the few slides so let's look at the code
几张幻灯片，让我们看一下代码
how this can be done so this time we
如何做到这一点，所以这次我们
create a configuration class this is why
创建一个配置类，这就是为什么
we need this first annotation at
我们需要在
configure add configuration we also need
配置我们还需要配置
to enable the scheduling by default
默认启用调度
spring is not scheduling anything the
春天没有安排任何
app schedule annotation would also not
应用时间表注释也不会
work without this annotation but in this
没有这个注释就可以工作，但是在这个
case when we have this one class it was
当我们有一个班级的时候
possible for configuration of the
可以配置
scheduling part of the application it
调度应用程序的一部分
makes actually sense to put this at
把这个放在
scale and a bit scheduling here in this
规模和一些调度在这里
place and not for example on the main
放置而不是例如在主要
class of the application and
申请类别
implementation of this method that I've
我已经实现了这种方法
already mentioned is is also pretty easy
已经提到的也很容易
because you have this object registrar
因为您有此对象注册商
and you basically call a method there
你基本上在那儿调用一个方法
are few methods on this on this
对此的几种方法
registrar one of them is cron at cron
注册商之一是cron at cron
task which basically does exactly the
基本上完成的任务
same as we see as we saw on the add
与我们在添加项中看到的相同
schedule annotation so you create a new
安排注释，以便您创建一个新的
chrome task another object which which
chrome任务的另一个对象
needs two parameters the first parameter
需要两个参数，第一个参数
is just the block block of code that we
只是我们的代码块
want to run with some schedule approach
想要以某种时间表方式运行
so we just process the events in our
所以我们只是在处理事件
case and the second parameter is the
情况，第二个参数是
cron expression that you want to say how
你想说的cron表达
often it should run so this code
它通常应该运行，所以此代码
basically does the same that we saw on
基本上和我们看到的一样
the on the previous with the first
上一个与第一个
approach okay let's let's look more into
好的，让我们来看更多
details how this could be improved so we
详细说明了如何进行改进，因此我们
believe that on in this over I already
相信在这之上，我已经
mentioned single responsible principle
提到单一责任原则
so this is why we thought okay the
所以这就是为什么我们认为可以
processing of the events or the
事件的处理或
definition how the events should be
定义事件应该如何
processed should be in a different place
处理后应放在其他地方
here we are writing a class that is
在这里，我们正在编写一个类
responsible for scheduling while another
负责安排另一个
class should be responsible for saying
班级应该负责说
how to do something when
当什么时候怎么做
when the when the job will be working up
什么时候工作会完成
and asked to do something this is why we
并要求做某事，这就是为什么我们
ideally it should be at least we think
理想情况下至少应该是我们认为
that idea it should be done like this
这个想法应该这样做
that you create you inject and meth you
您创建的注入和方法
inject an object a beam basically which
基本上向物体注入光束
is a runnable but by the net because
是可运行的，但由于网络
there is a name match it will it will
有一个名字匹配它会
work you could also use instead of
您也可以使用而不是
runnable you could use the proper proper
可以使用适当的适当的
class name the a dual season and then
班级名称为双季，然后
this object that you have available now
您现在可用的这个对象
in your scheduled class you can use it
在您安排的课程中，您可以使用它
inside the inside a method that you need
内部所需的方法
to overwrite so basically this is
基本上这样覆盖
exactly the same as you saw on the
与您在
previous slide but now the split is much
上一张幻灯片，但现在拆分很大
clearer and the class that we need to
更清晰，我们需要的课程
schedule the job that we need to
安排我们需要的工作
schedule can be defined now in a
时间表现在可以在
different component which is a task for
不同的组件，这是一个任务
us and we just say ok it has to
我们，我们只是说好，它必须
implement a runnable interface because
实现可运行的接口，因为
it requires to run something so this is
它需要运行一些东西，所以这是
why you run the code inside inside this
为什么在其中运行代码
one method that you need to implement ok
您需要实现的一种方法
having that we can we can move on and
有了我们，我们可以继续前进，
see what are the benefits of this of
看看这有什么好处
this approach so first we already saw
这种方法，所以首先我们已经看到
tax tasks all now scheduled in one place
现在将所有税务任务安排在一处
we have one class everything is inside
我们有一堂课，一切都在里面
new person comes and see clearly ok
新来的人来看清楚
these are the tasks that we are having
这些是我们要完成的任务
it's pretty easy to understand what's
很容易理解是什么
happening in the background the
发生在后台
additional benefit is a custom executor
额外的好处是自定义执行器
service this one was completely not
服务这是完全没有
discussed on the first approach because
在第一种方法上讨论，因为
there is no way to to handle that only
没有办法只能解决
with programmatic approach you can
使用程序化方法，您可以
create your custom executor service that
创建您的自定义执行器服务
should run the tasks that you have in
应该运行您拥有的任务
the background and when the application
后台以及何时应用
grows maybe you have lot of tasks
成长，也许您有很多任务
running in the background especially
特别是在后台运行
tasks but take a lot of time and maybe
任务，但要花很多时间，也许
you need multiple threads to process the
您需要多个线程来处理
these tasks and with the up scheduled
这些任务以及预定的时间
approach with the first approach there
那里的第一种方法
is only one thread so if you have
只有一个线程，所以如果你有
disproved this problem basically you
基本上证明了这个问题
need to switch to a programmatic
需要切换到程序化
approach let's look how this can be
方法让我们看看这是怎么回事
implemented so now we have this
实施，所以现在我们有了这个
Registrar again configure task method
注册服务商再次配置任务方法
that we need to
我们需要
right and now instead of calling on the
现在，而不是呼吁
Registrar at cron we call set scheduler
cron的注册服务商称为集合调度程序
so now we are saying okay
所以现在我们说好
don't use the default single threaded
不要使用默认的单线程
executor service but use this new one
执行服务，但使用这一新服务
that we would provide you and again we
我们会为您提供一遍又一遍的
some little bit of shuffling and putting
一些洗牌和推杆
this to the separate method maybe of
这可能是单独的方法
another class if someone prefers a new
如果有人喜欢新的课程
task scheduler method will provide you
任务计划程序方法将为您提供
the executor service executor service by
执行者服务执行者服务由
the way if you are not familiar with
如果您不熟悉的方式
that is just a class that tells how it
那只是一个讲述它如何的类
will handle the jobs how it will create
将处理工作将如何创建
the threads how many threads it will
线程将有多少个线程
have and yeah basically will handle
有，是的，基本上会处理
something in the background and in this
在后台的东西
case we are creating using as executors
我们作为执行者创建的案例
class with a static method new scheduled
静态方法的类新计划
thread pool so we will say please create
线程池，所以我们会说请创建
for us a thread pool that will work with
对我们来说，一个线程池将与
a scheduled items and it will have for
预定的物品，它将有
example four threads now we can set it
示例四个线程，现在我们可以设置它
like that and we can also as an
这样，我们也可以
additional benefit create a name for
额外的好处为
this for this for these threads that
对于这些线程，
will be used by this executor so here
将由该执行者使用，所以这里
this code is unfortunately not coming
不幸的是这段代码没有来
from the from the JDK itself here you
来自JDK本身的
need to use guava to use this builder
需要使用番石榴才能使用此生成器
but that's just implementation detail
但这只是实现细节
but here as you can see we can create a
但是正如您所看到的，我们可以创建一个
name format for this for this thread and
此线程的名称格式，以及
also with the percentage D at the end
也以百分比D结尾
which means that it will be a different
这意味着将会有所不同
number for each of these four threads
这四个线程中每个线程的编号
and when you will do some debugging or
以及何时进行调试或
checking on the life application how is
检查生活应用程序如何
the things happening in the background
后台发生的事情
you can see in the logs that this is
您可以在日志中看到这是
actually happening in the in the in this
实际发生在
in the scheduled process so this gives
在计划的过程中，所以这给
you a little bit increase on the
你增加了一点
observability having these two benefits
具有这两个好处的可观察性
in mind the the another point that I
考虑到我的另一点
would like to talk about is the
想谈的是
convenience of testing previously we
以前测试方便
didn't look at the test at all we didn't
根本没有看测试，我们没有
have anything
有什么
this is why I didn't want to discover
这就是为什么我不想发现
anything of that but here we actually
任何东西，但在这里我们实际上
can do pretty good testing so now we
可以做很好的测试，所以现在我们
could create a scheduled config test a
可以创建预定的配置测试
class that will basically test if this
基本上将测试是否
is what we want to do configure for a
这就是我们要配置的
first scheduling this is how it could be
首先安排这是可能的
done so I'm here using traditional
完成，所以我在这里使用传统
approach so the makita I'm saying on the
的方法，所以我在上面说的麦田
first line that this class this test
第一行，这个课程这个测试
should run in a mockito j-unit runner so
应该在模拟J单元跑步者中运行，所以
we can use mocks and the class that is
我们可以使用模拟和类
under test is of course scheduling
被测当然是排定的
config we are marking it that it will be
配置我们正在标记它将会
possible to inject mocks on this class
可以在此类上注入模拟
and we need two mocks to have it
我们需要两个模拟来拥有它
verified the first mock is the Registrar
验证了第一个模拟是注册器
on which we will put the on which will
我们将放在
call all this this logic that we want to
称这些为我们想要的逻辑
schedule and the second part will be the
时间表，第二部分将是
tasks that we want to actually schedule
我们要实际安排的任务
and the simple test that would verify
以及可以验证的简单测试
that everything is scheduled as we want
一切都如我们所愿
would just call this configure task
只会调用此配置任务
method passing by this task registrar
此任务注册器传递的方法
mock and at the end of the test we need
模拟，在测试结束时我们需要
to of course verify something and what
当然要验证一些东西
we will verify is just we will check if
我们将验证只是我们将检查
on this mock and method up grunt has
在这个模拟和方法的咕gr声中
cost called and basically if unleased
成本，如果没有租赁，基本上
on this method these two parameters were
在这个方法上，这两个参数是
passed so the first met this first
通过了，所以第一个遇到了第一个
parameter will be matched by the class
参数将由类匹配
type and the second will match basically
类型和第二个将基本匹配
by the string and now if someone changes
通过字符串，现在如果有人改变
that changes the cron expression because
更改了cron表达式，因为
I don't know typo or whatever now this
我现在都不知道错别字
test will we will verify that it it's
测试，我们将验证它是
what we want to have another test so we
我们想要再进行一次测试，所以我们
introduce the we introduced and use
介绍我们介绍和使用的
executor service and this one also can
遗嘱执行人服务，这也可以
be tested this is this is the the power
经过测试，这就是力量
of programmatic approach you need more
程序化方法，您需要更多
code but you have much more control so
代码，但您拥有更多控制权，因此
here again Makita runner to use the
这里再次牧田赛跑者使用
mocks using the same class on the test
在测试中使用相同的类进行模拟
injecting the mocks and here we need
注入模拟，这里我们需要
only one one mocked class because when
只有一个模拟课，因为当
you will lose another trick so
你会输掉另一把戏
in the test before running the the test
在测试之前进行测试
usually is that part time for
通常是兼职
preparation of the test so in the
准备测试，以便
preparation phase of the test we will
测试的准备阶段，我们将
create a captor a captor is a type of an
创建抓捕者抓捕者是一种
object that can check if something was
可以检查是否有东西的对象
executed with these parameters that we
用这些参数执行
can verify at the end and we are just
可以在最后验证，我们只是
creating a captor for a class that we
为我们创建的班级创建一个捕获器
want to check so we know that we are
要检查，所以我们知道我们是
expecting a scheduled thread pool
期待一个预定的线程池
executors this is why the for class
执行者，这就是为什么要上课的原因
parameter is is used with this in this
参数与此一起使用
in this case and again testing the code
在这种情况下，再次测试代码
you need to run it the same as us on the
您需要像在我们上一样运行它
previous test configure tasks and
先前的测试配置任务和
passing this the smoke and at the end we
通过这烟雾，最后我们
verify and assert so first what we need
首先验证并断言我们需要什么
to do is actually capture the value into
要做的就是将价值捕捉到
the capture that we defined at the
我们在
beginning of the test so we are saying
测试的开始，所以我们说
okay please verify that this mock was
好吧，请确认此模拟是
called was called with the method set
用方法集调用了
scheduler and this argument was passed
调度程序，此参数已传递
there and in this sense it's only a
从这个意义上讲，这只是一个
captor and only having that we can
俘虏，只有有了我们，我们才能
assert that this captor contains the
断言此绑架者包含
value this is why we call in gate value
值，这就是我们调用门值的原因
so we are taking the value from the
所以我们从中获取价值
captor and we are asserting that the
绑架者，我们断言
value that was passed there has a pool
那里传递的价值有一个池
size equal to four again additional
大小等于四再增加
benefit if someone changes the pools or
如果有人更换游泳池或
maybe remove the method out at all and
也许完全删除该方法，
making this scheduler a single-threaded
使此调度程序成为单线程
as the the default implementation this
作为默认实现
test will find it here we are finally
测试会在这里找到它，我们终于到了
back to the original problem original
回到原来的问题原来
problem as you remember we had multiple
您记得的问题是我们有多个
nodes and we wanted to have a single
节点，我们希望有一个
note that when it wakes up it tells us
请注意，当它唤醒时会告诉我们
that ok this is the node that is the
好的，这是节点
leader so as you can imagine having the
领导，所以你可以想象有
full control of the of the code we don't
完全控制我们不执行的代码
need to add any annotation animagic that
需要添加任何注释动画
is somewhere deep in the code we just
在我们刚刚编写的代码中
can write the code inside here this is
可以在这里写代码是
why when you add a cron task on the
为什么当您在
scheduler on this register actually you
这个寄存器上的调度程序实际上是您
just pass into the executable that is
只需传入可执行文件即可
inside the first parameter of the cron
在cron的第一个参数内
task you just can do whatever you under
您可以做任何事情
so we can just do this at this condition
所以我们可以在这种情况下做
if this leader again now I want to show
如果这位领导人现在又要展示
you a little bit improvement how this
你有点改善
can be done
可以做到
no more like spring way so this is why
不再像春天一样，所以这就是为什么
we we can introduce to other classes
我们可以介绍其他课程
that that can separate all the logic
可以分离所有逻辑
into different parts and keep the
分成不同的部分，并保持
responsibilities separated so here we
责任分开了，所以在这里我们
say okay this is a scheduling conflict
说好，这是安排冲突
class so this class should only be
类，因此该类仅应
responsible for the scheduling part this
负责调度部分
is why we are injecting again here the
这就是为什么我们在这里再次注入
process event task as on the previous
与上一个一样处理事件任务
slides and inside the configure tasks we
幻灯片和内部配置任务
are creating a new class which we could
正在创建一个新的类，我们可以
name leader aware task decorator so a
知道名称领导者的任务装饰器，所以
decorator that will that will create an
装饰器，将创建一个
object out above our our task that we
反对超越我们的任务
want to run and it will check the logic
要运行，它将检查逻辑
itself and only this this runnable we
本身，只有这可运行的我们
will schedule in the end in the
将会排在最后
registrar so now we will have three
注册商，所以现在我们有三个
parts first part is the scheduling that
第一部分是调度，
you see the the third part is that we
您看到第三部分是，我们
already had which is the the process
已经有这是过程
event task and in the middle we have
活动任务，中间有
this leader aware decorator and this is
这个领导意识的装饰师，这是
how it could look like a pretty simple
它看起来如何很简单
code at least this part of it that we
至少对我们的这一部分进行编码
have another runnable it's just another
还有另一个可运行的
another runnable as we can pass to the
另一个可运行的，因为我们可以传递给
cron tasks and it will it needs member
cron任务，它将需要成员
that basically it will run it in a
基本上它将在一个
specific condition that this is why we
这是为什么我们的特定条件
need this private runnable delegate so
需要这个私人可运行委托
that the code that will delegate to
将委托给的代码
constructor needs to of course pass it
构造函数当然需要通过它
to the to the method it passes to the to
传递给的方法
the field and inside the run method we
字段和内部运行方法
can now put the logic of checking how
现在可以把检查
the node is a leader here and only
该节点仅在此处是领导者
process the the task here and then we
在这里处理任务，然后我们
will just call delegate run to the last
只会调用委托运行到最后
part of the of the whole whole picture
整个图片的一部分
okay so we had this one approach then we
好的，所以我们采用了这种方法
had the second approach everything was
第二种方法是
fine it was it was it was working but
很好，那是它正在工作，但是
actually we found out that it still it's
实际上我们发现它仍然是
still not perfect it's still a problem
仍然不完美，这仍然是一个问题
especially when there is a network
特别是在有网络的情况下
partition or someone calls it
分区或有人称它
some people call it a split brain
有人称它为裂脑
problem this is why I want to show you
问题，这就是为什么我想给你看
this this looking may be complex but it
这个看起来可能很复杂，但是
will it will be clear in a second how
一会儿会清楚吗
this problem can can appear so up up to
这个问题可能会出现直到
down is the timeline how the time is
时间表是时间如何
passes and the lines the vertical lines
通过和垂直线
are basically the different components
基本上是不同的组件
of the system so we have this
系统的，所以我们有这个
Orchestrator which keeps the information
保留信息的协调器
which instance is a leader and we have
哪个实例是领导者，我们有
two instances and let's say at some
两个实例，让我们说一些
moment at time instance one is who wakes
在某个时刻实例是谁醒来的
up because it wants to run something and
因为它想运行某些东西而
because we use this is let's say run if
因为我们使用它是说如果
leader annotation or the second approach
领导者标注或第二种方法
it asks before processing something it
它在处理某些东西之前会询问
asks Orchestrator okay should I proceed
问Orchestrator好吧，我应该继续吗
orchestrate the response yes you are a
协调响应是的，你是一个
leader now so instance one starts and
现在是领导者，因此实例一开始，
starts to process the event but in the
开始处理事件，但在
meantime before it finished this
在此之前
processing Network partition happens
正在处理网络分区
metal partition basically means that
金属隔板基本上意味着
these these two nodes cannot communicate
这两个节点无法通信
with each other anymore
彼此在一起
and Orchestrator how how the logic of
和Orchestrator的逻辑如何
keeping not equipping keeping the
保持不装备
information if the note is the leader is
注释是否为领导者的信息是
basically keeping as open session
基本上保持公开会议
between these nodes and usually it
在这些节点之间，通常
requires to check if the health endpoint
需要检查健康终点
of the node is is fine it's broken let's
的节点是好的，它坏了，让我们
say in this case then Orchestrator what
说在这种情况下，然后Orchestrator
it needs to do of course select a new
它当然需要选择一个新的
leader so this is what happens here the
领导者，这就是这里发生的
session has broken Orchestrator things
会话破坏了Orchestrator的内容
okay let's notice down it cannot be a
好吧，让我们注意到它不可能是
leader anymore we need a new one so it
领导者了，我们需要一个新的，所以
selects a new leader and in anyway
选择一个新的领导者，无论如何
usually it's the oldest node but in this
通常是最旧的节点，但是在此
case it's not important so it selects
情况并不重要，因此选择
instance two now and then in some time
实例二不时
few seconds let's say later the instance
几秒钟后再说实例
two now wants to process this in a
现在两个想要在一个
scheduled way and ask Orchestrator am i
预定的方式并询问Orchestrator我是
a leader and of course the cash register
领导者，当然还有收银员
yes because he's just selected it so
是的，因为他只是选择了它
instance two processes the event and
实例二处理事件
stores it into the external service and
将其存储到外部服务中
at the end also suddenly instance one
最后也突然实例一
was really really slow but it wasn't
真的很慢，但是不是
down also wakes up and saves this to
下来也会唤醒并将其保存到
external service what can happen now we
外部服务现在会发生什么
have two events
有两个事件
on the external service usually business
通常在外部服务上
case you shouldn't have this case you
如果你不应该这样
shouldn't allow that so how we can how
不应该这样，所以我们怎么可以
we can handle that how we can improve
我们可以处理如何改进
the resiliency I love the solution of
我喜欢的弹性解决方案
course there is even this previous slide
当然，甚至还有上一张幻灯片
was maybe a little bit complex but we
可能有点复杂，但是我们
can think of something much much simpler
可以想到更简单的事情
let's say we have this scheduled job
假设我们有这份预定的工作
that tries to save something to the to
试图保存一些东西到
the external service and the response
外部服务和响应
didn't come it's just a normal HTTP call
没来，只是普通的HTTP调用
let's say and the response didn't come
比方说，回应没有来
so what the node can know what the not
所以节点可以知道什么
what the node can do that does it no it
节点可以做什么就可以了
can repeat if they repeat then we'll
可以重复，如果他们重复那么我们
have to duplicate entries right so can
必须复制条目正确，所以可以
we even safely repeat how we can make
我们甚至安全地重复我们的制作方法
sure that the repetition will not make
确保重复不会
the whole business logic broken we have
整个业务逻辑破裂了
to basically be sure that there are no
从根本上确保没有
duplicate entries created in the
在中创建的重复条目
external service and the solution to
外部服务及解决方案
that is usually some kind of ID which is
通常是某种ID
mostly named that is an it's an identity
主要是命名这是一个身份
idempotency ID this is why we need to be
幂等ID，这就是为什么我们需要
sure that the action that we are
确保我们所采取的行动
performing isn't it idempotent
表演不是幂等的
idempotent in this sense in this case it
在这种情况下，幂等
means that the action that we will pass
意味着我们将通过的行动
that the action that we will perform or
我们将执行的动作或
the item that will pass to the external
传递给外部的物品
service will contain some unique ID and
服务将包含一些唯一的ID，
having this ID the external service can
具有此ID的外部服务可以
say ok I already process that so I will
说好，我已经处理了，所以我会
skip it and send it back to you response
跳过它并将其发送回给您
it's a duplicate but no harm done there
这是重复的，但没有伤害
was nothing stored twice this is why we
什么都没有存储两次，这就是为什么我们
with implementation of that we can now
通过实施，我们现在可以
say one or multiple identical requests
说一个或多个相同的请求
give the same result so now even if you
给出相同的结果，所以即使您现在
repeat it 100 times of course assuming
当然重复100次
that you provide the same ID each time
您每次都提供相同的ID
now the external service will be sure
现在，外部服务将确保
that it will do not happen and the
它将不会发生，并且
previous case with this network
此网络的先前案例
partition wouldn't be handled correctly
分区将无法正确处理
because if we provide the same ID - with
因为如果我们提供相同的ID-
- with tune from two notes the same the
-两个音符的音调相同
the same entry only once will be created
同一条目只能创建一次
and because we we split it and I hope
因为我们将其拆分，所以我希望
you remember from the beginning we store
您从一开始就记得我们存储
everything in the database so this is
数据库中的所有内容，所以这是
the moment what you should create an
当你应该创建一个
item potency ID so whenever you have
项目效用ID，因此只要有
something to process you generate a new
需要处理的东西会产生一个新的
ID and when the event is being sent by
ID和事件的发送时间
any node it uses this ID and then this
它使用此ID的任何节点，然后使用此
will be sure we can be sure that it will
可以确定，我们可以确定
be not a problem for us okay talking
对我们来说不是问题好吧
about different solutions we also want
关于我们也想要的不同解决方案
to always talk about some improvements
总是谈论一些改进
what could be what could be handled
什么可能是可以处理的
better so first improvement that we were
更好，所以我们先做了改进
talking thinking about is that actually
谈论的是
maybe we can distribute the jobs if the
也许我们可以分配工作，如果
amount of items to process is suddenly
待处理的项目数量突然增加
growing maybe we should handle this by
成长也许我们应该通过
different nodes multiple in multiple
不同的节点多个
multiple nodes basically at the same
多个节点基本相同
time so first idea that came to mind to
时间，第一个想到的主意
to my colleagues was that maybe we can
对我的同事来说，也许我们可以
just use we have already PostgreSQL it's
只需使用我们已经有PostgreSQL的
the source of true of the events to
事件真相的来源
process so maybe we can use it to to
过程，所以也许我们可以用它来
basically say ok this is the way how you
基本上说好，这就是你的方式
can handle that and this is the source
可以处理，这就是来源
of true if if if the node if the node
如果节点是否为真，则为true
should process it or not and in our case
应该处理还是不处理，就我们而言
we had a progress SQL database so you
我们有一个进度SQL数据库，所以您
can use a for update clause
可以使用for更新子句
so whenever a node is taking something
所以每当一个节点拿东西时
from the database to process it can mark
从数据库中对其进行处理可以标记
the rows to process that they are being
要处理的行
taken for update and another node it
用于更新和另一个节点
will if it will go through the events
是否会经历事件
checking if the nodes if the items
检查节点是否项目
should be processed or not it will just
应该处理还是不可以
skip the locked items but here like one
跳过锁定的项目，但就像一个
cover here it looks good but actually
盖在这里看起来不错，但实际上
there can be a performance problem
可能存在性能问题
because if you mark many rows with the
因为如果您用
update then another another node need to
更新然后另一个节点需要
basically either rate through all of
基本上任何一个都通过
them and skip all skip skip these so
他们并跳过所有跳过这些
maybe then performance will be improved
也许然后性能会提高
but at the end it may be it can be also
但最后可能是
a problem so this this is not
一个问题，所以这不是
discovered way to handle that maybe we
发现了可能解决我们的方法
need to to think about better ways to
需要考虑更好的方法来
handle that because another solution
处理这个，因为另一个解决方案
that we were thinking of and and works
我们在思考和工作的
in one one of our systems is the sq SQ
sq SQ是我们系统之一
which is a queue solution or any other
这是一个队列解决方案或任何其他解决方案
queue basically you would what you can
基本上，您会排队
think of and the SQS queue could be a
想想，SQS队列可能是一个
source of true of the items
项目真实来源
so whenever the stream consumer would
因此，只要流消费者
consume something it would be put into
消耗将被放入的东西
desk USQ and it could be taken by the
桌上USQ，它可以由
different instances and process it could
不同的实例和过程可以
work because we we know I mentioned that
工作，因为我们知道我提到
the instance if it's taking it it marks
实例（如果有）标记
it invisible for the other ones but here
它对其他人不可见，但是在这里
the another problem is that sqs queue is
另一个问题是sqs队列是
not a full database it's just a queue
不是完整的数据库，只是一个队列
and the maximum time that an item can
以及一个项目可以使用的最长时间
store in SQL is 14 days so in the worst
在SQL中存储是14天，因此在最坏的情况下
case scenario when the events are really
事件确实发生的情况
really slow or there is an issue in the
真的很慢，或者有问题
application or I don't know that maybe
应用程序，或者我不知道
someone is on vacation and will not look
有人在度假，不会看起来
on the queue the event will just
在队列中，事件只会
disappear so maybe it will scale
消失了，所以也许它将扩大
properly but maybe it will not perform
正确，但也许不会执行
it's it's logical so what are the
这是合乎逻辑的，那是什么
lessons learned that that we had with
经验教训，我们与
this short short session annotation
这个简短的短期会议注释
driven development always with care so
始终谨慎地驱动开发
looks easy it's convenient but you need
看起来很简单很方便，但是您需要
to be aware that there are some
要知道有一些
drawbacks consistency of the code is for
代码一致性的缺点是
sure something that it's important we
确保重要的事情我们
like to to use the same approaches or
喜欢使用相同的方法或
this sure the way that you create your
这肯定是您创建自己的方式
being and then you can inject it so
然后你可以注入它
having this in mind makes the code
考虑到这一点使代码
easier to maintain and easier to
易于维护且易于维护
understand for new members of the team
了解团队的新成员
and we can also think about resilience
我们也可以考虑弹性
many times here mentioned so for example
这里多次提到，例如
the the general idea here kinases the
这里的一般想法激酶
stream
流
this increases resilience because we are
这增加了弹性，因为我们
no longer having this synchronous
不再同步
communication between services but we
服务之间的沟通，但我们
just send events and the predictability
只是发送事件和可预测性
also grows because ServiceNow can say ok
也会增长，因为ServiceNow可以说确定
I process this event and I'm just done
我处理了这个事件，我就完成了
no problem with the response that is not
没有问题的响应没有问题
calm
平静
and things and also we can think about
和事情，我们也可以考虑
observability which is one example here
可观察性是这里的一个例子
I mentioned this thready naming so when
我提到了这种线程化的命名方式
you look through your locks especially
你特别看你的锁
in a big application it can be it can be
在大型应用程序中可以是
it can be a benefit when you when you
当您当您
have a lock marked with a proper thread
有标有适当螺纹的锁
thank you very much for the henshin and
非常感谢您的henshin和
if you might few minutes for the
如果您可能需要几分钟的时间
questions I there is question the mic is
问题我有问题的麦克风是
coming basically I want to ask why ask
基本上我想问为什么问
us q and not something else if your
我们q而不是别的，如果你
problem was that you cannot start the
问题是您无法启动
data more than 40 days so you think like
数据超过40天，因此您认为
some other complete solution or like
其他一些完整的解决方案或类似
other Q or what do you mean yeah I mean
其他问或你的意思是对的
yes why why not Kafka or something yeah
是的，为什么不选择卡夫卡呢？
yeah I thought Kafka so so in our
是的，我认为卡夫卡在我们
company we don't use it yet
公司，我们还没有使用它
so maybe as an let's say third iteration
所以也许可以说是第三次迭代
that could work I agree that Kafka is a
那行得通，我同意卡夫卡是一个
really good solution but because we
很好的解决方案，但是因为我们
don't have it yet in our company at all
我们公司还没有
so first the problem of installing it
所以首先是安装它的问题
maintaining and basically having this in
维护并基本拥有
our in our system and also now people
我们的系统，现在的人们
need to learn that and yeah because we
需要学习，是的，因为我们
are on AWS we usually try to use the
在AWS上，我们通常尝试使用
components that are available there
那里可用的组件
but I agree Kafka would be probably will
但我同意卡夫卡可能会
will solve a lot of problems here thank
将在这里解决很多问题，谢谢
you
您
how do you solve the problem when the
您如何解决该问题？
orchestrator is down good question
协调员不好的问题
so in our case we we had a solution
所以在我们的情况下，我们有一个解决方案
other solution that has that is also
具有的其他解决方案也是
distributed basically in the through
基本上分布在
third system you need to distribute
您需要分发的第三个系统
everything and and just this note was
一切，而这个笔记是
also scaled so there was no single note
也缩放，所以没有单个音符
so there was no single point of failure
因此没有单点故障
of course maybe all the notes can go
当然，也许所有笔记都可以
down but ideally you want to scale it
缩小，但理想情况下，您希望按比例缩小
out so there should be if you use for
出来，所以应该有，如果您使用
example by no Mongo or Reddy's you have
没有Mongo或Reddy的例子
some secondary nodes that can help in
一些辅助节点可以帮助
this case so yeah it shouldn't be so I
这种情况，是的，不应该这样，我
maybe my picture was a little bit not in
也许我的照片有点不在
details but basically it's not a single
细节，但基本上不是一个
note it's like a single place in the
请注意，这就像
system but it can be different a few
系统，但可以有所不同
notes that that does the same and can
请注意，该操作相同并且可以
can switch between them so you mean a
可以在它们之间切换，所以你的意思是
cluster of orchestrators yeah ideally
理想情况下，协调器集群
cluster of orchestrate oh yeah all like
编排哦，是的，所有人都喜欢
if this is a redis that side then you
如果这是redis那边，那么你
have just basically distributed to the
基本上已经分发到
database thank you and I was wondering
数据库谢谢，我想知道
if an ESB would help you to keep in
ESB是否可以帮助您保持现状
order things in the whole process
在整个过程中订购物品
have you considered it could you repeat
你考虑过可以重复吗
the beginning of the question and I was
问题的开始，我当时
wondering if an ESB enterprise service
想知道ESB企业服务是否
bus would help you to keep in order
巴士将帮助您保持秩序
things in the world process so
世界上的事情如此
Orchestrator item scheduling and items
Orchestrator项目计划和项目
and so on so I have to say that I don't
等等，所以我不得不说我不
know it's it's something that we didn't
知道这是我们没有的东西
consider for sure I don't know that
考虑一下，我不知道
there are some solutions but maybe maybe
有一些解决方案，但也许
are we are still not on this level of
我们还没有达到这个水平吗
complexity here that the amount of
这里的复杂度
traffic is not there yet that we need to
交通还不存在，我们需要
introduce something complex the what
介绍一些复杂的东西
what exactly is what kind of solution
究竟是什么样的解决方案
did you have in mind
你有没有想过
what could you name one for example mule
你能给什么命名，例如m子
is be using connectors one connector for
正在使用连接器，一个连接器用于
each
每
tasks at us executors would be one for
在我们执行者的任务将是一个
Orchestrator obviously class setting
协调器显然是班级设置
solution what's the name of this
解决方案这个叫什么名字
solution ESB such as a mule mule mule
ESB解决方案，例如a子
occur example yeah so yeah again another
发生例子是的，所以又是另一个
improvement may be to when especially
改善可能是到什么时候
when the amount of the jobs is
当工作量是
increasing and processing of that is its
它的增加和处理
high then for sure thank you looks like
高，那么肯定谢谢你看起来像
a thank you very much for the questions
非常感谢您的问题
[Music]
[音乐]